domdex.com 2017-10-04

# Magnetic Privacy Policy

## Summary of Privacy Policy

_At Magnetic, we are in the business of knowing what you’re interested in so that when you’re visiting websites or receiving e-mails from companies that work with us, we can show you content that is more likely to be relevant to you.  We collect and use information from across the web and beyond to help us give our customers insights into what types of products you are interested in purchasing.  We also employ a variety of tools to try to figure out which browsers or devices belong to you so that our customers and partners provide you with a consistent experience everywhere – on your smartphone, tablet, laptop or other connected device. To help us do this, we may collect your IP address, e-mail address, and other information about you or your devices. We value your privacy, and you have the right to opt-out from certain of our services, as explained in [Section 6](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#consumercontrol). Please note that this does not mean you will see less ads or get fewer e-mails; it just means that what you see will be less relevant. _

## Full Privacy Policy

**Updated June  9, 2016**

Magnetic Media Online, Inc. (“Magnetic” or “we”) is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals. This policy applies to Magnetic and provides information about our Services, the information we collect, how we use and share that information, your rights, and how to contact us. This privacy policy covers our collection and use of information relating to a natural person that we collect on our websites and through relationships with our Customers and Partners.

**1\. MAGNETIC’S SERVICES**

Magnetic provides marketing and advertising services used by retailers and other businesses. Through relationships with our customers (“ **Customers** ”) and partners (including without limitation online or mobile ad networks, ad exchanges, marketing platforms, and data partners) that we and our Customers and partners work with across the web (collectively “ **Partners** ”), we collect information about online activity related to search, website, and shopping behavior which enables us to deliver in-store product recommendations, personalized email marketing services, audience and customer analytics, and personalized advertisements (which is sometimes referred to as “targeted advertising” or “retargeting”), and to analyze the effectiveness of these services. For the purposes of this privacy policy, these practices are referred to as our “ **Services**.”

**2\. THE INFORMATION WE RECEIVE AND COLLECT TO PROVIDE OUR SERVICES**

To provide our Services, we collect and receive a variety of data from, and on behalf of, our Customers and Partners.  This includes the following information, referred to collectively as “ **Service Information**.”  (To learn about the information collected on the Magnetic Websites, which is distinct from our Service Information, please go to the Section titled [“INFORMATION COLLECTED ON THE MAGNETIC WEBSITES AND HOW WE USE AND SHARE IT.”](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#informationonthemagneticwebsites))

**a. Unique Identifiers**.  We may collect unique user identifiers from your browsers or devices.  This may include, for instance, a unique identifier associated with a cookie on your browser, or a mobile advertising identifier associated with your mobile device, such as an Apple IDFA or an Android Ad ID.  For more details on how these technologies work, please see the section below regarding [“COOKIES, PIXEL TAGS, AND SDKs.”](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#cookiestagssdks)

**b. Log Information**. Similarly, when you visit the website of a Customer or Partner, or a website where our Partner’s services are deployed, our servers may automatically collect information from your browser. This may include information such as your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address (a unique number automatically assigned to your computer from which your location can be inferred), date and time, whether one of our cookies is already set on your browser, browser type, the website (or mobile application) with which you are interacting, search data, webpage information, and your interactions with our Services, Customers, or Partners.

**c. Data Segments.**   We do occasionally create or offer (for ad targeting or analytics usage) Data Segments regarding general health-related interests (such as diet, fitness, or smoking) or customized health-related Data Segments to help determine which ads a person might be interested in. A list of those segments can be found here.

**d. Transactional Information**. Our Customers may provide us with information about your transactions and interactions with them or their websites.

**e.  ** **Mobile data.** Through our Partners and mobile applications using our Services, we may collect information about your interactions with those applications (including your IP address and time-stamp information), and information about your mobile device (including device type, handset name, operating system information, mobile identifiers such as Apple IDFA and Android Advertising ID, app-specific identifiers, and a list of the applications your device interacts with.  Sometimes, this may include precise location information, which may be categorized into interest categories based on vicinities your device tends to visit.

**f. Email Marketing Information.**  When we provide email-related Services, we may collect information regarding how you interact with emails sent by, or on behalf of, our Customers, including information relating to the opening of the email and clicking on recommendations contained in the email.

**g.** **Data Enhancement and Combination.**  We may combine the Service Information listed above, or enhance it with other information that we obtain from other sources, to improve our Services.  When we do this, we often use data “hashing” and other methods to de-identify or obfuscate certain types of information,  such as email addresses.

**3\. HOW WE USE AND SHARE THE SERVICE INFORMATION**

We use the Service Information as follows:

**a. Provision of Services**. We use the Service Information to provide our Services (which we describe at the beginning of this Privacy Policy) across multiple media and advertising channels (also described in this Policy).  For instance, we use the Service Information to enable our Customers to better tailor ads to their own customers and prospective customers, which may include sending or serving ads through email, display media, in-site recommendations, or direct mail.  To do this, we may use de-identified, unique identifiers that enable our Services, and we may work with our Partners to do so.  These identifiers can often enhance consumer privacy by enabling us to maintain or associate data through de-identified or obfuscated information. 

******b.** **Creation and Sharing of Data Segments**.  We sometimes use the Service Information to create Data Segments (described in Section 2), which may then be used by Magnetic, our Customers, or our Partners to tailor advertising, marketing, and other services.  By way of illustration, if we collect Service Information that indicates that you enjoy the outdoors, we may then send, or help our Customers send, targeted ads or emails regarding outdoor gear or travel ideas. We also may create data models that indicate that many people with similar attributes to you (such as geographic or interest-based) seem to like the outdoors, and we may then send them ads regarding outdoor gear or travel ideas, based on that same model.

******c.** **Sharing and Syncing Information Across Platforms and Devices.**  We may share Service Information by integrating it (or Data Segments) with Partners to grant access to advertisers and Customers in conjunction with analytics or marketing services they provide. This might be done by syncing identifiers to permit de-identified data that we collect to be used by these platforms and their customers.  Likewise, we may obtain data from our Partners, such as browser or mobile identifiers and associated information; this process may involve the sharing of unique identifiers to create the sync. We may do this to provide Customers with this data or to improve our Services.  Similarly, we or our Partners may use other information collected through the Services (for instance, IP addresses), aggregated with information collected from various unaffiliated websites, mobile applications, and various devices or browsers, to provide content and advertisements about goods and services of interest to you across those devices and browsers.  

**d. Customers and Partners.** We may share Service Information with our Customers and Partners so that they can improve their offerings and services.

**e. Agents and Service Providers.** We may share Service Information with agents and service providers acting on our behalf so that they may provide services to us. For example, we may use a third-party database provider to store Information.

**f. Research.** We may share or disclose Service Information in de-identified form in connection with our research and development efforts.

**g. Corporate and Legal Compliance.** In addition, we may share or disclose Service Information for the following limited purposes:

  * As part of a business sale, merger, consolidation, investment, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation, or in connection with steps taken in anticipation of such an event (e.g., due diligence).
  * With our corporate affiliates.
  * When required by law or in response to lawful process, such as a subpoena, or to cooperate in good faith with a request from a government or law enforcement agency or official.
  * If we believe sharing the information may prevent physical, financial or other harm, injury or loss; or we believe is necessary to protect our, or any other person’s or entity’s, interests; or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity.

**4\. INFORMATION COLLECTED ON THE MAGNETIC WEBSITES AND HOW WE USE AND SHARE IT**

**a. The Website Information We Collect**

We collect the following information from visitors to our websites (the “Magnetic Websites”), including the website on which this Privacy Policy appears (“Magnetic Website Information”):

  * **Volunteered:** You may share information with us on the Magnetic Websites when you request information from us, fill out a form on our website, or interact with us in other ways.  This information may include personal information, such as your name, email address, and other contact information. 
  * **Passively Collected (e.g., Cookies and Unique IDs):** We use automated mechanisms (e.g., cookies and pixels) with unique identifiers to keep track of visitor interactions with the Magnetic Websites.  (You can learn more about these technologies below in the Section titled [“COOKIES, PIXEL TAGS, AND SDKS”](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#cookiestagssdks)).  We may use third party-services such as Google Analytics, in which case those third parties gather information such as your IP address, browser type, the webpage from which you came to our website, and the times of your access to the Magnetic Websites.  In addition, as you browse our websites, advertising cookies may be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in.  Our display advertising partners may then help us retarget ads to you on other sites based on your interactions with the Magnetic Websites.  To “opt out” of having your information used to tailor ads to you in this way, review the Section below titled [“CONSUMER CONTROL AND OPT OUT OPTIONS](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#consumercontrol)[ **”**](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#consumercontrol) to learn how to opt-out of these services and instead receive generic, non-tailored ads.

**b. How we Use the Magnetic Website Information**

In addition to the uses described above, we use the Magnetic Website Information (alone or in combination) to provide, market, and operate the Magnetic Websites and Services.  Among other things, by collecting the Magnetic Website Information, we are able to:

  * Maintain and offer access to the Magnetic Websites and Services and optimize the way the Magnetic Websites and Services are offered to our Customers.
  * Send you information about our products and services, including marketing communications.
  * Respond to your questions, concerns, or customer service inquiries.
  * Provide you or your customers with our Services.
  * Customize the content and advertising you see on the Magnetic Websites, across the Internet, and elsewhere.

**c. How We Share the Magnetic Website Information**

We may share the Magnetic Website Information as follows:

  * As part of a business sale, merger, consolidation, investment, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation, or in connection with steps taken in anticipation of such an event (e.g., due diligence).
  * With our corporate affiliates.
  * With third parties that help us to provide the Magnetic Websites or Services, such as entities that help us make the Magnetic Websites or Services available and functional (such as hosting services); entities that help us make available or transmit any information we hold (such as helping us send emails, process payments, and manage customer information); and entities that help us (including our contractors, agents, and affiliates) provide technical, customer, billing, administrative, event planning, marketing or operational services to us or our Customers.
  * When required by law or in response to lawful process, such as a subpoena, or to cooperate in good faith with a request from a government or law enforcement agency or official.
  * If we believe sharing the information may prevent physical, financial or other harm, injury or loss; or we believe is necessary to protect our, or any other person’s or entity’s, interests; or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity.
  * We also may disclose your information under circumstances not mentioned here with your prior consent.

**5\. COOKIES, PIXEL TAGS, AND SDKS**

  1. ******Cookies and Pixel Tags.   **Cookies are small data files containing a string of characters, such as an anonymous unique browser identifier.  Cookies are stored on your computer or other device and act as unique tags that identify your device or browser. Our servers may send your device a cookie when you visit the Magnetic Websites, and our Customers and Partners may do likewise on our Websites, our Customers’ and Partners’ websites, and elsewhere.  A pixel tag (also commonly known as a web beacon or clear GIF) is an invisible 1 x 1 pixel that is placed on certain web pages. When you access web pages on which a pixel tag is deployed, the pixel tag may generate a generic notice of the visit and permit Magnetic, our Customers, or our Partners to set or read cookies.  Pixel tags are used in combination with cookies to anonymously track the activity on a website by a particular browser on a particular device. If you disable cookies, pixel tags simply detect an anonymous website visit.  Magnetic, alone or with our Customers and Partners, may use cookies to, among other things, “remember” you (e.g., when you visit the Magnetic Websites or the websites of our Customers or Partners), track trends, and collect information about how you use our Customers’ or Partners’ websites or interact with advertising.  We use cookies to provide relevant content to you and replace non-relevant ads with ads that better match your interests.
  2. ******Mobile Device Identifiers and SDKs.**  We may use or work with Partners who use mobile SDKs to collect information, such as mobile identifiers (e.g., IDFAs and Android Advertising IDs), and information related to how mobile devices and their users interact with our Services and those using our Services.  A mobile SDK is in effect the mobile app version of a pixel tag or beacon.  The SDK is computer code that app developers can include in their apps to enable ads to be shown, data to be collected, and related services to be implemented.  We may use this technology, for instance, to analyze or measure certain advertising through mobile applications and browsers based on information associated with your mobile device.  If you would like to opt-out from having ads tailored to you in this way on your mobile device, please follow the instructions in the below Section titled [“CONSUMER CONTROL AND OPT OUT OPTIONS.](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#consumercontrol)[” ](http://www.magnetic.com/about/privacy/#consumercontrol)

As described in Section 3, our Customers or Partners may use the above technologies (sometimes, in combination with each other or other data such as IP addresses or hashed or de-identified data files) to coordinate identifiers across platforms, browsers or devices, to more efficiently analyze or target advertising.

**6\. CONSUMER CONTROL& OPT-OUT OPTIONS**

Consumers have control over whether or not they would like to receive relevant advertisements and marketing email from our Customers.

**a. How to  ** **Opt Out from Targeted Advertising**

_To opt out of receiving personalized ads from Magnetic, please visit  _[ _http://www.magnetic.com/about/opt-out/_](http://www.magnetic.com/about/opt-out/) _ _

_To opt out of receiving personalized ads from Magnetic and other advertising companies, please visit_[ _http://www.aboutads.info/_](http://www.aboutads.info/)

_Other consumer choice tools are provided through the Ghostery Enterprise opt-out program (available at<http://choices.ghosteryenterprise.com/global-opt-out.html>)._

Please note that opting out does not mean you will block online advertising altogether or see fewer ads. It simply means that the ads that you see will not be personalized for you. Ads may be served because they relate to the website you are visiting or to your current search, or they may just be randomly placed.

Your choice to opt out from personalized ads placed by Magnetic will not affect ads placed by any other organization. 

We comply with opt-out requests by placing an “opt-out cookie” on your computer or device. Consequently, if you clear your cookies on that computer or device, we will not be able to read our “opt-out cookie” and will resume collecting information from that computer or device for purposes of retargeting. Similarly, an opt-out request will not be effective on other browsers, computers, or devices you may use if you have not opted out while using that browser, computer, or device.

**b. How to Opt Out from Receiving Emails from Our Customers**

You can opt-out of receiving future emails that we send on behalf of a specific Customer by following the “Opt-Out” or “Unsubscribe” instructions in the emails we send. Please note that your opt-out preferences apply with respect to that customer only. 

**c. How to Opt Out on Mobile Devices**

You may be able to opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of mobile behavioral advertising, by accessing the “settings” on your Apple or Android mobile device, as follows:

Apple Devices:  If you have an Apple device, you can opt out of most app-based tracking for interest-based advertising by updating to iOS 6.0 or higher and setting Limit Ad Tracking to ‘ON.’ You can do this by clicking on Settings -> General -> About -> Advertising and toggling Limit Ad Tracking to ‘ON.’ 

If you have an Android device, you can opt out of most app-based tracking for interest-based advertising by opening the Google Settings app on your device, selecting Ads, and then selecting the option to opt-out of interest-based ads.

**7\. DATA RETENTION**

We retain Service Information for as long as it remains relevant (in our discretion) to providing our Services. However, for most of our Service Information, this period is 24 months.

**8\. MAGNETIC’S INDUSTRY MEMBERSHIPS**

Magnetic is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance in the United States (“DAA”) and Canada (“DAAC”) as well as the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and adheres to their Codes and Principles.  For more information about how online advertising affects your privacy, see the [“Understanding Online Advertising”](https://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising) page on the NAI website. For information about the Self-Regulatory Program For Online Behavioral Advertising and to learn more about the Ad Choices icon, visit [http://www.aboutads.info/](http://www.aboutads.info/). For more information on the DAAC program, please visit [http://youradchoices.ca](http://youradchoices.ca/).

**9\. HOW WE PROTECT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We employ security measures to guard the information we process against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, alteration, disclosure, access, or other use, and we comply with applicable security requirements. However, despite the measures we take, no security measures can be 100 percent secure; we therefore do not warrant the security of any information provided to or collected by us.

**10\. DATA TRANSFERS AND INTERNATIONAL USE**

Our Services are hosted by servers located primarily in the United States. We may transfer Magnetic Website Information and Service Information to countries other than the country in which that information was originally collected for purposes such as storing and processing information, responding to your inquiries, and operating our Services. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country from which the information was initially collected. 

**11\. CONSUMER PRIVACY RESOURCES**

To learn more about how your browser can help maintain certain privacy choices, please visit the appropriate link below

**12\. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

Magnetic reserves the right to change, modify, and add terms to this policy at any time. We will post changes on this page, and if we determine that they are material in nature, we will provide more prominent notice on our homepage and indicate at the top of the policy when it was most recently updated.  Changes we determine to be material to this policy will become effective 30 days after posting.

**13\. QUESTIONS ABOUT OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Magnetic is responsible for the processing of personal data we collect about you in relation to our Services. If you are located in the European Economic Area or certain other jurisdictions, you may have the right to request access to, rectification, or deletion of the information we maintain about you, within the limits of the applicable law(s), and you may also have the right to object to the processing of the personal data we collect about you. If you would like to exercise those rights or if you have any questions or concerns related to our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Email: privacy at magnetic dot com

Magnetic Media Online, Inc.

360 Park Avenue South, 19th Floor

New York, NY 10010

USA

Telephone: 212-757-3189
